Hello everyone, how are you?
Today I'm going to bring you a video showing how
install VSCode.
For those who code on the machine and such, use the
Linux to do this
software development,
be it Java, Node, PHP,
whatever language it is,
It's interesting to have VSCode.
I like VSCode.
Other people use other software,
but VSCode I
I think he's pretty cool.
It is very useful, works well.
I'm here with Ubuntu 24.04,
I will show you
how do I download VSCode
and install it on Ubuntu.
So let's look for him here
on Google, VSCode.
Go to the official VSCode website,
I click on download here.
Then he's already appearing here for me
Windows options,
Linux and Mac. Okay.
As I'm on Ubuntu,
I'll download a .deb .
What are these options here? The .deb would be
for Debian and Ubuntu, okay?
For these versions that are based on it,
Mint and such.
The .rpm , Red Hat, Fedora, SUSE.
.tar.gz is the source.
And Snap is like a... like it's a Snap
Store, as if it were a Marketplace.
Something like this, so you understand, to make it easier.
But let's download our .deb .
And here is the architecture,
okay? So let's download the .deb for x64.
I downloaded it here. VSCode.
There you have the code .deb file.
Now, how do I install our VSCode here?
I come here to
the shell. Then I'll do a "sudo" to
I have root permission to
be able to install this package. I give a "dpkg",
what is the command to be able to do
installing our VSCode .deb.
"-i", which is the
parameter to tell me what I want to install.
Then I give Downloads/code, which is
the name of the file I downloaded.
I press "Enter".
It will get the .deb as if it were an .exe,
a file
binary. He's going to sue this guy
and will do the installation. If he
there is a dependency error,
it will notify us on the screen and we will
having to fix this dependency error
to be able to continue.
If he can do it all alone,
there won't be any error. He is
asking for installation here,
if I would like to use a repository.
It has a repository, it's cool,
let's use the repository.
Yes, it's been a while since
I didn't install VSCode.
Okay, let me see if he put it
the repository right here.
Or if he just gave the message
to give it a go there.
Let's see what he did here.
It's been a while since I
installed VSCode,
he put it there man, cool, it's there,
this line that
he put it here, it's really cool,
he already puts it on automatic man,
very cool, you had to do everything by hand here,
OK, here he puts it
the deb, the architecture and places where
that he has,
he will catch,
when you want to update VSCode now,
this is really cool,
I was surprised,
I didn't know they had improved that.
I give one
update here,
it will update all repositories
software that I have already installed.
And if I upgrade here, assuming that this
is a new version of VSCode,
leave it closed, the software,
close VSCode,
give an update and you give an upgrade.
He will get the last packages,
he's not catching it even here
VSCode is picking up other things,
but it's the same thing.
You give it an upgrade and it will update
the package list, like here
that he updated the VSCode ones,
These are these guys here from Microsoft.
It updates this list of packages and here
with the upgrade, it downloads the new packages, okay?
If you
need to update VSCode later, that's how it is.
So now,
Let's open VSCode. Let's see it working.
I click here
Below, show applications.
I will type
up here. VSCode.
There's the guy.
Okay, it's running.
It works just like Windows, okay? It's the same thing.
You can install the
plugins, right?
You can come here and manage it,
put plugins.
For those who use Git, right?
Just like me, I work with DevOps, right?
So I use it too,
I like him.
For those who use git, you can commit
around here and such,
You can add your projects and commit now
Here you can add plugins to see
the shape of your project, to be able to see
your project better, to become more
visually interesting,
so it works the same as
Windows, it's the same thing, cool.
Another thing I want to show you is
seeing that it is running, and there is a little red ball here,
Why is it running?
if I close it here,
he will disappear from the bar
here, it disappeared, so I want to leave it fixed
here on the side supposing, I want to leave
he fixed it like I left Discord there,
OK then I open it again
VSCode, I run it
VSCode, open it and it's here
I want to leave it fixed,
Right click on the pin icon
so he has the red ball,
it is there running now if I close it
he's here he's still there, so what
I can come here and drag this guy,
put it wherever I want, cool
so the next time I want to run it again,
I can or run
him here, or I can come
and call him here directly
in the bar, I can click on the live bar,
it will work the same
So you don't need to come down there
and look for it to execute it directly
So, this is the video I wanted to bring you today.
It's very easy,
This installation is much easier
than it was before.
I enjoyed it too much. It's the video I wanted to bring today,
how do you install the
VSCode, because I needed to use it, okay?
Because I have things to do
also. On my desktop here,
I have things
channel to upload to Git.
Thank you to everyone who has watched this far. We're together.
Subscribe to the channel, share
and enjoy our content there.
I will be bringing more content,
more interesting now about the
DevOps area and such. It's going to be really cool.
Hug. Stay safe.